All right.
Okay, let's call this budget workshop meeting to order at 07:01PM.
And let's start with the pledge of allegiance. The
pledge allegiance Pledge allegiance to the flag
>> The United States Of America. And
to the republic
for which it stands.
One nation under
God,
indivisible,
liberty,
justice for all.
Right.
>> Eric, do we have anybody for public speak here?
I think we have.
You appear to have Elaine Bucard and
Anne Cermey.
>> Okay. Hi, miss Elaine. I just joined in to to give a listen.
Oh, okay. Thanks. Okay. Yep.
>> This is Anne from a.
I just
want to say I support the budget that was approved by the boe.
Okay.
Anything else just that
just that.
Okay.
The only budget.
Okay. Thanks for attending.
>> Okay,
that appears to be everybody you have for public speak.
>> Okay, perfect.
All right,
let's jump into the budget.
I'm just quick correction,
Eric for you
On this, I found an error on one of the lines. Row 684,
which is the AES Board of Education budget.
The department request number is wrong.
It should be
4000122787.
Went back and looked at the
requested presentation from February 9 and that's what the what they requested.
We fix that column G.
Yep.
>> And then fix the dollar change and the percent change,
h and I as well.
That
changes in both automatic.
Okay.
Alright.
>> Getting some background noise. Do we have everybody on mute? That phone number? Oh, Joann, go ahead.
>> I was gonna ask about a change too, Diane. I'm not sure if I'm right or not,
but
if you,
the revenue,
you know, that revenue sheet where you can see the mill rate,
I had asked,
I hope that was- Hold on one second.
>> Mayor, can you mute that phone number?
I think because it's unmuted.
Where
are we getting the feedback from? Okay. I'm not sure.
Right. On the revenue tab. Okay. Yep. The revenue tab
>> where we had talked about the 100,000
as the place marker for the fund balance.
Yes. I
mentioned this to Eric yesterday. I saw that at the top. Maybe I'm looking at a wrong spreadsheet. I saw the 100,000 at the top. When you go down to the bottom and you calculate,
I just don't have it in front of me to give you a line, but when you go down to the bottom
where it says fund balance 2223,
I thought I saw 250,000
there.
So row 42.
This should be the spreadsheet
>> on my. So this should be the spreadsheet from Eric dated
04/14/2022.
Okay.
Row 42 use of fund balance
two fifty was for 2122.
And then the green. You're
>> right in this for twenty twenty two, twenty three,
two fifty you're right that's a good thank you
>> I know I saw it but I
don't check today Eric and I saw it again so I wanted to bring it up because that'll affect the calculation
Maybe. Are
you talking about the green column column I?
>> Let me. No, she's talking about line 78.
Thank you. Oh,
>> 70 eight. Oh,
70 eight. Oh, okay. Because up up on 42,
it's right.
>> Yeah. Okay. I'm on 42 too. Okay. So you're saying 78
column H,
that two fifty should be 100.
100.
Okay.
Good catch.
Eagle eyes.
All right.
>> And I don't remember, by the way, we talk about putting 100 there?
We talked about a placeholder for 100.
Okay.
I've obviously forgotten. Sorry. Well,
I can't remember what I did yesterday, Rob.
Right.
All right.
Any other things that anybody saw?
>> We're getting that feedback again. I don't know what's going on. Sounds
>> like somebody's television almost like.
All right.
Other than that, Eric, I have one other question for you.
On the mill rate calculation,
you're
row 65.
Correct.
And you have the difference, the calculation to make up the difference between what the actual mill rate was and what we charged.
Get the difference between the two mill rates as
0.13,
not 0.12.
Well,
>> zero- And then you have it multiplying
it by 271,447,
And the spreadsheet says 1 mil for that year was 271,446.
So can you just check that math and make sure
we've got the right numbers going into that calculation?
Sure.
Well, I get 36 mills.
Subtract 35.87
is 0.13.
Okay.
>> So,
so if we can just
make sure and then the the mill, the dollar amount, the $2.71 $4.04 7
in column j,
the spreadsheet says on line 62,
column g, that it was $2.71 $4.04 6.
So, if we can just fix that note and the calculation because I think you have that calculation going into the mill rate calculation.
Yeah.
>> Yeah, we have it minus 1.104,
and it's gonna be a hair more.
I will redo the calculation.
Alright.
>> Okay. It's at most gonna change the mill rate by point o one.
>> Right, it's like nothing but.
All right.
Right.
Does anybody have any questions
on the spreadsheet,
on the budget or anything that anybody wants to talk about?
Joanne?
>> I'm going to have a couple of things that I'd like to discuss, but I don't always want to be, you know, I don't know if anyone else wants to ask their question first.
>> What do you want to jump to the front of the I
>> know, because I have several, I don't wanna,
I guess basically
I don't know. I don't see anyone unmuting.
Is the 707 number, is that Marina?
The phone number? The phone number Marina.
>> Okay.
Hello, Marina.
I mean, I know we're gonna be open for discussion and all, but since we're talking about that mill rate page,
am I coming through clear to you all?
I can hear you okay. Thank you. Because when I listen back to the tape on,
that's posted on the website, a lot of times my
speech is garbled when I say something.
And so I'm hoping that during the meeting,
it's not like that.
So thank you. I just wanted to make sure.
So
obviously we're looking at this budget, just one overall thing that I wanted to
say is
I was, you know, doing some calculations on the mill rate
and different things. I know Eric will give us the final numbers, but, you know, we just need to, we know how much we have to raise by taxes and how much, you know, by looking at the sheets, what the percentages are going to be.
A thing that's
making it seem less than it is, if we had this, if a mill was, if we didn't have the reval in town,
this would be,
I believe, between an eight and a 9%
increase,
you know, so it's it's pretty hefty.
>> Hold on. Stop, stop, stop.
Wait, total amount we're asking by taxation
is increasing in this budget 5.7%.
>> That's irrespective of the mill rate. I'm not allowed to make a comment, Mr. Manager.
No, no, I'm I just didn't even finish.
Okay.
>> Sorry. I mean, I'm making, I, I just,
you know, I just think I need to stop for a moment. So go ahead, I
just didn't even get a thought out. I just, you know, you have no idea where I was going.
I just was doing some calculations
based on if a mill was, you know, it's,
whatever we do approve eventually
is based on
the new, you know, the reval rates. And it's just so up and down, you never know. It's all I was gonna say. I mean, really don't have,
I have other questions
that I was gonna say. I'm a little taken aback, so I'm kind of stumbling through my words.
Know, say we were trying to pass this much spending through and it wasn't a revalue year,
the increase would be, it would look a lot worse. Clearly that is how you make a budget
and it's based on the new mill rate, the new reval list,
the new grand list,
whatever it is. I was just making an observation
that it would've you know, in a nonreval year, it would've been a lot higher.
>> I mean, I I think that the
to Eric's point is that in a nonreval year, 5.7%
increase would be that's what it would be.
Right?
>> That's all I meant. I don't know why I got the stop, stop, stop or whatever. So
anyways.
Okay.
>> But respectfully
respecting everyone's position.
Yeah, that's, I mean, this is true numbers. I'm not saying it's not, it's just a big increase in spending, that's all.
And I'll sit back. I do have more things to talk about, but I'm gonna take a moment.
>> Anybody else have any comments
they wanna share?
No.
Well, I'm looking at this budget, and I'll just give a high level summary of how I think about it right now. You know, this is a budget coming off of budget year of a zero percent increase last year. So this budget
reflects
everything we need to do.
You know, it's a significant increase,
but we had no increase last year.
So
this is really something that's going to go to the taxpayers from my point of view
and say,
do you want to spend the money on what we need to do get that get it done. So
we can get the roadwork done and get what we need accomplished.
So this is really,
you know, a budget
trying to accomplish the plan put in place by the Board of Selectmen to get the roadwork done and, you know, and keep pushing that envelope up. We had a little derailment
last year of not being able to get any increase put through last year. So this is kind of where we fall now.
And I think it's up to the taxpayers to decide how they want to spend their money
when we get to referendum.
>> Any other
questions, comments,
Joanne? I a question. Go ahead, Louise.
>> Are we gonna discuss the Andover school budget
or is that?
>> There
is, okay, so what we can do is the school budget as it's presented is one number for us. We can't cut any specific line items, but we can cut the total dollar amount
and make a change there if we chose so choose.
Okay.
Does that answer your question?
>> Yeah, but is that gonna happen prior to us? I mean, I'm okay with the way the budget is now presenting it to the town,
but I didn't know if there was any outstanding
questions or concerns about the school budget.
>> All right.
I do have some concerns about the school budget.
And I will tell you since,
and I'll just tell you where I'm coming from on that.
Since the
move by the town to stop the shared financial service
jobs.
I think
we could easily cut
$20,000
from the school budget,
because the position that's going to be left over the school is not a director or finance
and treasurer of the town.
School can do whatever it wants with that position because it's their position. After we go our separate ways as of June 30,
and they can do what they want. But if you know you were to hire.
It's not the same job anymore.
So really,
it's not that high paying of a job, and the roles and responsibilities of that job has
totally changed
going forward.
And I think it would be prudent to make a an adjustment there and let the school
figure out how they want to deal with it. I don't think it won't impact the kids won't impact the quality of education is just an administrative
job.
And they can choose to
do what they want with that job and craft it any way they want. It's their purview.
But I don't think we need to fund it at the same level it was
in the budget.
Are they going to be
any changes responsibility for her
>> since after Well, Eddie will be working after June 30,
that director of finance job is gone.
Sherry will only be working at the school and doing school work.
And we will go back to just having an assistant
position which will be Marina on the town side.
And we did put a placeholder in the budget for a part time treasurer.
Okay.
Yeah. So,
>> we do not need a full time treasurer, we're too small in town.
I think that makes sense, Diane.
Yep. I agree with that as well.
>> Yeah, since I have one. Go ahead, Joanne. I'm sorry, did I miss any of the conversation at the beginning?
I realize that there are, that was a great point Diane and I know that they're changing the positions and there won't be as many, know, the responsibilities are going to be different.
So was there any conversation because we know that's not changing till the fiscal year ends?
I mean I know I just did I miss any conversation tonight to see if
you know.
No we're bored at night so I don't want to ask things that aren't appropriate to our topic tonight but. Oh okay
>> As far as I know right now, there is just, you know, a whole transition
going through from now until June 30. Right. Because it's
>> still staying the same until then. And then like you said in next year's budget,
the position is going to be totally different and not So
that makes perfect sense.
>> Okay.
So reducing that down, what would be the effect
of the mill rate
and the percentage of increase
that we're asking for the town? If we made a change, it
would be pretty small.
>> I just plugged it into the spreadsheet. Lowered
the school budget increase a little bit to 5.1%,
but it didn't
really have any
significant impact.
It didn't change the decimal even on the overall budget
impact unless I did them unless I the spreadsheet didn't propagate properly. But $20,000
is
know, out of a 10.10
and a quarter million dollar budget
doesn't do much. But, you know, look, every little bit counts and
if that's what you guys wanna do, that's fine. I I assumed we would come here tonight and some people would have ideas for
this or that.
I personally am
on board with the idea of, generally speaking, taking what we've got in front of us to the town and
trying to
explain that, as Diane said,
after a zero budget last year, here we are.
But it's
not a big difference, I don't think.
>> All right.
I'm on a motion right now to
reduce the school budget by $20,000
to $4,102,787
Do I have a second?
I'll second it. Who
>> said it first?
Someone else can. Is that you, Rob?
That was Kurt. Kurt second. Okay.
So I made the motion Kurt second.
Let's any discussion. Do we have any discussion on this? Anybody have any questions or concerns?
>> No, basically it just makes sense based on the conversation we just had the position and the responsibilities are going to be
totally different. So we can't fund that position at that same level. That's all. Nothing to do with the school budget itself, just the change that
came about this year. So that's my discussion. It makes sense.
Anybody else?
>> That that number of 93,730
stood out stood out to me.
Is that is that the actual salary
that they had set for her at the school?
>> I believe if it's in that finance
position
on their budget, that is the salary for that job.
What do you got to do to get it?
I
don't know, Kern.
>> That's a that's an awful lot of money. It's more than she was making doing the the duel.
>> No. I think that I don't know what that probably included a raise. I don't know what her current salary is now,
but that was what was being budgeted going forward.
>> I agree, Kirk. I'm not sure where the figure came from either. It was definitely lower the year before.
>> The year before figure was $77,600
and I believe that was just Laura's job because
Laura was still,
I believe employed when the budget was done last year for the school.
>> And I don't think her salary was included even as an FYI on the personnel
spreadsheet that we got. So we can't tell.
Right.
Okay.
So
>> any more discussion on this?
We
call for a vote?
All in favor?
Aye. Aye.
Linda, Kurt,
Joanne.
Aye.
Louise. Yes.
Okay. Rob.
Almost, I'm gonna abstain.
>> Okay.
So there are one, two, three, four,
five yeses,
one abstention,
no, nos.
Motion passes.
Okay.
If we can get that updated
on the spreadsheet as well with those other corrections we have.
And Eric,
for you, do you want to correct this spreadsheet and then have us,
unless anybody has any other changes they wanna make,
have us vote on it next week?
Or do you guys
wanna see the spreadsheet one more time?
>> Are we still discussing the budget in general. I was letting the whole school talk go by but I was gonna ask to see something since we're all together.
Okay, the sheet, I mean just to see
a few weeks back.
I mean, like you said, I'm in favor of
probably moving forward with the budget as it is. And then obviously the townspeople and townsfolks are going to have their say,
But there was,
Eric had provided us with something on the public works.
And I had it, that's why it was frustrating to me to sign me on tonight because I had it that I had a couple of questions on.
It might have been an overview
of the dollar amount and what it's spent on, and it might have been in the board of selectmen packet.
You're talking about a sheet that was put together that said what we spent last year, what we're gonna spend this year? Yeah, yeah. And I just was, you know, since we were together, I was going to kind of take a look at that because that's another,
you know, the hot ticket item or a big ticket item that we know
a lot of spending is going into. We've heard all the reasons. I'm not saying I'm,
totally understand what they're trying to get done, but that was something that I was gonna ask a couple of questions on my own and then I just couldn't get my hands on it.
Can we ask our town administrator if he might have that available to share with us?
>> I mean, I can look and be taking a couple minutes to look through and see right And
>> I apologize, I really wanted to have it in my hands and I did earlier today.
Let me see if I have it really Thank you. Because if that gives us in case I had any last minute questions on that budget wise.
Let me go see if I have it.
I
>> have everything else. I did a quick search of my email. I'm not not quite sure. How how how long ago was this? I feel like it was a couple weeks ago. It was once you have the patient's
>> Was what Diane was when we had the public works presentation.
Yes, yes.
>> Hold on.
I have a roadwork report hold on.
Oh, I have it.
Thank you.
So
>> if I can share my screen, I can try doing that. Share screen.
Post disabled.
Hang on.
You should be able to share now.
>> Can you guys see this?
Can you see the screen?
Yes. Yes.
Thank you. That's exactly what I'm So it's this.
>> Oh, this is just one year though. It's not the one with the updated.
Okay.
>> This is last year,
and then the one for this year is, July.
>> Okay.
I think that's a good document to track down though, for the purposes of the public hearing. Yeah.
When you're talking about,
you know, where's the, where's the meat
in the town budget this year,
right? Public works is it. So you
know that this is your backup. Well, sorry. This year's version of this document
is your backup in a way to discuss it with the public to say, look, you know,
this is why,
you know, we're increasing the public works expenditure to get some things done to try to catch up. I'm
sure anybody in town
can think of a pothole somewhere
or something more serious than that that they'd like addressed and this might help us
get through that.
>> I'm trying to find that document, I cannot find it. I know, I thought it was a two page sheet.
Really was I not
>> have it in hard copy, but I don't have it. See, I can't get my hands on it, but I'm just don't why I have it in my phone. I don't have it
in my
directory here.
Alright, this is
>> I mean, I'm sure we'll track it down
between
everybody here.
It was,
know, Joanne mentioned something about the selectman. Maybe that's where it went
and got pulled from, Diane. I don't know. I didn't see it in a quick perusal of my emails, but frankly, I get behind and things get buried.
>> Right.
Right.
That document
was presented to the Board of Finance first.
Mhmm. And and
last month or the month before when the board of selectmen had questions,
I just forwarded them the same
note from Jay to them.
Right.
>> So you did get that.
I'm trying to see whether I can find it real quick.
Yeah. We definitely had it. I can't remember
where I saved it to.
Oh, crap.
>> And if
we don't get our hands on it, I mean, I'll find it afterwards
and my questions can be answered. It just
tells the needs of the town.
One other thing while you're looking,
I would just like to see, since this probably won't be a long meeting tonight, I'd love to see the,
if someone could share
the revised,
what we would be, just that revenue sheet and shows the mill rate and all the things that I was bringing at the beginning of the
meeting,
just to kind of visually look at it again and make sure that I'm not forgetting. Are we able to do that? Share that one?
Because we found that one fun balance, different thing that I brought up. So I just kind of wanna make sure there wasn't anything else that I was gonna question.
>> Oh, you're looking for this. I think I may have found it.
Okay.
Here's my email here
Friday, March
18.
Okay. From Eric with two documents attached. Second one
is a two page document, three page actually, sorry, document.
It does start with the 2021
Road and Tara Roadwork Cost Report, but if you scroll down
there's the twenty
twenty two-twenty twenty three Road Improvement Request
and that is
707500.
Thank you, Brian. So I have it here.
If anybody wants to go through their emails, it's it's March 18 from Eric.
>> I do not
have that in my emails right now.
>> Just I cleaned suppose I could hit reply to all and pass it back on.
Or if you want me to share my screen, I mean.
>> Either way, I mean, I know I'm jumping around at some point, I wanna look at this document
And then maybe since Diane has this up, can we look at this?
>> And then we could Oh, this is the revenue tab from the budget worksheet.
Yeah.
Do you want to look at here.
So we're, I
>> want to make it, let me make mine bigger. I just, I just forwarded it right replied to all on that and sent it and hopefully
saw the attachment comes through.
Thanks Rob for doing that. I got it Rob.
Thank you.
>> Is the attachment in there Kurt sometimes my Gmail is weird about that. Oh, no, maybe not. Nope, no attachment.
Hold on. I'm looking.
No attachment.
>> Alright, I'll I'll fix that. Give me a sec. You guys talk about this.
>> Yeah.
So my only questions, Diane, were I'm
assuming
is this the changes have been made. Right?
And going to make those changes. Right. So Right. And then right. So we'll make those changes, and then we'll look at the final numbers. Is that what we're And then we'll have a final
>> workbook.
Okay. You know, Excel spreadsheet. Does that work for everybody?
Yes.
And then everybody you know, it shouldn't be long.
It should be fairly quick for Eric to make those changes. Then we'll have, you know, two days to look at it over and then we can
review everything
and make our final decision next Wednesday
because it's on the agenda.
Are
you good with that guys are.
>> That sounds fine with me. Yeah.
Yeah, I guess if I had had any, that's fine with me. Thank you for bringing this back up.
I thought there was something else I was gonna point out, but there isn't, it was just that one. I knew it was in one place than the other. So thank you for that. And then,
yeah, I guess I just wanted an overview of looking at the public works document if someone, but you don't have that now or you do?
>> Still working on hold on.
I don't know why I can't find it. Hold on.
I don't have that one in my email.
So
>> I made the mistake of closing it and I'm, you know, I'm losing it in the clutter. Give me a give me a minute and I'll find it.
>> Just
quickly scrolling through my stuff to see if I can pick it up real quick.
Yippee.
No, I don't have them in here.
What was the date of that email? March 18.
>> I have the email,
but it doesn't have an attachment.
Oh, here we go.
>> I got it. I got it.
Okay,
let's go back to this.
I'm sharing my screen again.
This is the one.
>> Yep. And I just attached it to an email. Hopefully, that's.
I I I had to download it off of it's so bizarre. I went into my sent folder. The email I sent you all, in my sent folder, the attachment show up. So I pulled it from there.
Anyway,
this is the this is it because, yeah, page one has this, but then if you scroll down Right. Yep. And then page two starts twenty two twenty three.
>> So, Joanne, can you see that?
Oh, you're on mute.
So what was your question?
>> I think I just wanted to look it over
and see
if I had any questions
of it. So again, I appreciate all of you looking and putting it up there. I knew like Rob kind of surmised for me or summarized for me that it is one of our big ticket items that, you know, a lot of questions will come on
for that. So I wanted to
be prepared.
That's all. So I now that we all know we at least have it, I want to look at that.
>> Yep, and again, you know, hopefully this time the email has an attachment.
Thank you. So you should be able to pull it up yourself.
I appreciate it. Yeah.
>> All
right.
Any
other questions that anybody has or anybody want to make any comment on the budget as it stands right now.
Go
>> ahead, Louise. Would it be possible to put that document we just brought up onto the website.
So in case people have questions ahead of time?
The public works document?
>> Yeah, on the budget,
on the end oversight under the budget issues.
Can we do that?
>> Think it's in the board of selection packet already, but I don't know, you know.
>> Would be the worst thing to have it with the budget,
but okay, I could go either way on that. I just think it should definitely be a part of our presentation.
>> Right, I mean, presentation hasn't been created yet so for the
>> hence why I'm saying it. We
have to, we still have to create it. Right, right.
>> All right.
Anybody else have any questions,
concerns, anything on this budget that you want to talk about? Plans are to have Eric make the changes we talked about tonight,
the corrections and the change to the school,
and
then we'll get a clean spreadsheet out to everybody.
And then
we will talk about this in the meeting on
Wednesday, next Wednesday.
>> Diane, I am formulating a question if you give me a minute. Sorry.
Just Okay. Have a
I want to ask it in the right way.
Okay. Right. Together in my because I'm going be talking. I'm going to ask Eric a quick question, but I want to formulate it right.
Okay. Thank you for allowing me a moment.
>> So next Wednesday, that's the
drop dead date for us to
>> Approve the budget to send it to the annual meeting. Right.
>> Eric, if I could ask you a quick question.
When I was looking at, you know, the employee spreadsheet
and the personnel spreadsheet, which goes over hours
and
different
things, I know we have the salaries.
Is
there
the the people such as like
the zoning agent, the wetlands agent,
guys that maybe work ten hours a week,
Are they involved in? They're not in Murph, right? They they follow the twenty hour rule as well.
Correct.
Thank you. They're not eligible for any benefits.
>> Because I know.
So let me just make sure there's no one else I wanna ask about.
And
>> I know that we raised the hour for the building department person,
the bill, not the secretary, but the actual building official.
What is his current hours per week that we raised it to?
Seven.
Correct.
>> Thank you. All right.
And someone like that's at the transfer station and does seventeen hours per week. So no benefits there?
Correct.
>> I sound like I'm a screw. I don't want to. I just want to make sure that I'm understanding
that it's a definite flat
twenty hours or above could be eligible, but anybody that I see on this spreadsheet that's under twenty hours would not be.
Correct.
>> Thank you.
Okay.
That's what I, that's all I would have Diane.
All right.
Anybody else?
Kurt, Louise, Rob?
>> I had a question
probably for Eric. Who's
our clerk tonight?
Marina is our clerk tonight.
Okay, thank you.
>> I'm good for now and you know I I think we gotta take it to the town and
see how things go. I'm loathe to
take a preemptive whack at this.
Okay.
That's just my perspective, very different than last year.
>> Okay,
anybody else?
Okay,
hearing none.
Let's move on.
I don't have any correspondence anybody get anything that they need to share.
No. Okay.
Okay, Eric, we're at public speak if we go around.
Okay.
First up, now Bruno
And Jerry's here.
>> If I could go first,
being the Board of Education chairman,
I'm kind of disappointed
that
the Board of Finance
felt the need
to cut us $20,000
I'm also very disappointed that you don't trust
our board
to come up with a responsible budget
in a responsible way
to
support our school
and to keep it going.
I
just don't understand this.
I know that we've if we come in with a zero increase,
it still doesn't matter.
You all want to cut the budget.
We can't keep going
in this direction.
Our expenses go up,
salaries go up,
and you know as well as I do that in your own personal households,
your expenses go up as well.
And if you are working for a salary for a dollar per hour or whatever dollar per hour you work for,
you'll find that with inflation going on right now, you probably are having a tough time.
And if you're on a fixed income, you're also having a tough time.
It's the reality of the economy
and
our town.
I support our town. I will
go out of my way
to support what the board of
education wants
and I will support whatever the town board of selectmen
want.
I know it's important.
I know it's important when I drive up Hendy Road every day and down Hendy Road.
I know it's important when I see what's going on on the roads and the bridges,
and I know that people cost money.
And you have to pay people a fair wage.
And I am
supportive of this town.
I will
go to my savings account
to pay you that's in taxes
what you need to support this town.
We need to be together
and the
divisiveness
is just not a good thing.
And I hope that you will take that with you and think about it and put it in your heart.
Because
it's disappointing
with that kind of behavior that goes on.
And that's all I have to say. Thank you for listening.
>> I'm equally as disappointed
that
the motion was made
to address what is really a school personnel
budgetary issue.
I know that the town had requested
multiple positions
because the town knows what they need.
I'm disappointed
that the reasoning is
that
we feel as a
board of finance that
that person's job is
up to us to decide what their responsibilities are going to be. Yes,
previous to the merger that was made, this cooperative agreement that was made between the town and the school prior to my even getting hired,
the
business person that worked here worked a point eight. But since that person has left,
we have been in constant transition.
Everything, you know, we got a new system admins, so it wouldn't have mattered if it was the former finance person,
or the current finance person, they would have needed time to adjust to that.
We have been in transition with the audit, and we've been in transition with the budget and the negotiations that we had last year.
And so I'm hurt
that the Board of Finance
would say, we don't think that that personnel person on the Board of Ed deserves
to be full time,
when that is a decision that's made on the school side for this year.
And so I am disappointed. And feel that that was a little bit of a personal
situation that was brought about. But
I
going forward would
just like to be on the record as stating that I do believe that that position being in transition
and the mere fact that it's going to start July 1, which is when the new school year begins to unmerge
and go back to what it was with all of these changes now from what it once was is unfair.
>> Okay,
thank you, Val. Next up, Tim B.
Tim?
Going once, going twice okay next up on my screen and creme I
>> feel the same way as Jerry and Valerie that
we you should not have cut that $20,000
that's the board of ed
budget and they spent a lot of time getting that budget
just right and then I don't think that you understand
what it is to cut that.
Think we it was wrong to have cut that that's all.
>> Okay and thank you and
next up on my screen, Kimberly Persson.
>> Hi, everyone. Thank you for your time tonight.
I completely
agree with the cut.
And I appreciate Diane doing that.
I also didn't have time to send a letter to the Board of Finance, but I will be sending one.
I agree with the cut completely.
Thank you.
>> Diane, that seems to be all the public that's on my screen.
>> Okay.
All right.
Any other
members of the Board of Finance have any other comments or questions or any concerns they want to air?
If not, we're ready for adjournment. Can I have a motion for adjournment?
>> Wait a minute. There's a Tim B on the screen as well. Is that public?
>> Eric did call on him, but he did not respond.
Oh, I didn't hear that one. Okay.
>> Okay, Joanne.
I just want to make sure. So we're saying that we'll
circle back to this next week, you know, with those adjustments. We've all made our decision on what we're gonna put forward. So we'll that will be part of our regular meeting. Right? And that's enough time before the public
>> meeting date that's already been established, right? I'm sure. Yes, have to take action on the budget next week. That's our drop dead date. Okay,
that was it. Thanks. Any
>> other comments? Any other questions?
Do I have a motion to adjourn?
I'll make the motion to adjourn.
>> Okay, Louise motion to adjourn. Can I have a second? Second it. We have seconds.
All in favor?
>> Aye. Aye.
Thanks Diane for stepping up on it. Thanks.
>> Thanks everybody. See you next week. Thank you. Bye bye. Bye. Bye bye.